ALERO AMOLIRE JEMERIGBE

SENIOR FINANCIAL ANALYST



9 Stephen Oshunlalu Street, Gbagada, Lagos, 100242, Nigeria







LINKS

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jemeri gbe-alero-71a3a048/

SKILLS

- Value-at-risk(VAR)
- Audit, Budgeting, Tax, Account, Financial Statement Analysis, IFRS
- Investment/ Money Market Analysis, Business Analysis.
- Advanced Excel for data analysis and manipulation
- Structured Query Language(SQL)
- Financial Modelling
- Financial Analysis
- Highly analytic and creative in solving problems
- Documentation and reporting
- Excellent communication skills.
- Forcasting Financial Statments
- Data Analysis
- Python

management and data analytics capabilities. I have been actively involved in financial analysis and modelling, reporting and management of fixed income securities of one of the most profitable Banks in Nigeria. I continue to play strategic roles around financial control, leading teams in projects with the responsibility of blocking financial loopholes with my expertise.

I am a Financial and Quantitative analyst with excellent leadership, investment

WORK EXPERIENCE

Guaranty Trust Bank Plc (GTBank)

Apr 2014 - Present Lagos

FINANCIAL CONTROL OFFICER

- Performed detailed review and analysis of the Bank balance sheet and income lines, carrying out variance analysis and providing reasons for the variance with key action points.
- Conducting Peer Review and detailed analysis of the Bank's Financial Statement.
- Actively involved in the Bank's smooth transition from IAS 39 to IFRS 9
- · Part of the Team that successfully developed the Expected Credit Loss (ECL) model required by IFRS 9, particularly in data gathering, modelling and estimating the risk parameters such as the EAD, PD, LGD and computation of impairment of the fixed income securities, Bank placements and Loans portfolio.
- Resolution of half and full year audit requests by liaising with both internal and external auditors and responding to specific requests.
- in Budget preparation and financial planning of all profit and cost centres of the Bank.
- Part of the two-man team that implemented the Value at Risk Model used in estimating market risk on trading portfolio of Fixed Income Securities and Foreign Exchange.
- Using the re-pricing gap analysis for estimating interest rate risk on non-trading portfolio.
- Properly Managed and monitored the Bank's Fixed Income Securities portfolio: Treasury Bills and Bonds (FVPL, FVOCI and HTM)
- Preparation of IFRS 7 Disclosures requirements and sensitivity report for both half year and full year account, particularly in the areas of Fixed Income Securities
- by Carrying out Daily, Weekly and Monthly analysis on Fixed Income Securities portfolio to ascertain the efficiency of the dealing room and to provide appropriate recommendation to Management. • Proofing of Investment Securities ledgers: Treasury

· Liaised and provided support to the trading desk team

- Bills and Bonds by computing the interest income/receivable, premium/discount and MTM to check the correctness of System postings. • Timely preparation and rendition of statutory reports
- and returns to the Regulators. • Mining of large financial data from the database,
- analyse the data, draw conclusions and provide recommendations to management. • Prepare concise analysis on the impact of released Key
- macroeconomic reports such as the Inflation, MPC and GDP reports on the Banks Business, as well as predicting the expected figures and possible areas of opportunities for the Banks Business.

Management Company Apr 2013 - Mar 2014 Lagos

Royal Exchange **Finance Asset**

· Successfully carried out trend analysis on the data and stock prices of various companies listed on the stock

QUANTITATIVE ANALYST

- exchange in making a buy or sell recommendation that assisted the Group in maximising its returns on its investments. · Properly managed the liquidity of the Group by
- placing its funds in Money market instruments like Treasury bills and other short-term placements with Banks offering a good balance of high interest rate and minimum risk level. • Carried out various quantitative and qualitative analysis for investment decisions.
- Preparing clear and concise report and supervisory document.

University of Lagos

EDUCATION

Lagos

Masters in Business Administration Major - Finance

MBA

CGPA = 4.31 / 5.0

University 2010 Ile Ife

Obafemi Awolowo

2016

Bachelors Degree in Mathematics

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

CGPA = 4.70 / 5.0 (First Class Honors)

COURSE

ACCA Global UK Feb 2019 - Present

ASSOCIATION OF CHARTERED

CERTIFIED ACCOUNTANTS(IN

PROGRESS)